Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 11.02.17 19:33:26
按照Elizabeth Kubler-ross的理论
according to  elizabeth kubler-ross,
我们在弥留之际
when we are dying...
或者面临巨大损失时
or have suffered  a catastrophic loss,
我们的悲伤会经历明显的五个阶段
we all move through  five distinct stages of grief.
- 首先是否认
- we go into denial... - push another amp of calcium.
再加一安的钙
Because the loss  is so unthinkable,
因为损失无法想象
- 我们无法想象惨剧真的发生了
- we can't imagine it's true. - Clear.
离手
然后对所有人感到愤怒
we become angry with everyone--
恨生还的人 恨自己无能为力
angry with survivors,angry with ourselves.
接着是交涉
Then we bargain...
该死 O'malley 挺住啊 活下来
damn it,o'malley.Come on. Live. Just live.
颅内压30
I.C.P.'S 30.
- 加70甘露醇 开始输液 - 出血渗透到脑干
- Push 70 of mannitol and start bagging. - he's hemorrhaginginto his brain stem.
现在用类固醇会不会太迟了?
Is it too late for steroids?
我们恳求
- We beg,we plead... - he's herniating!
- 疝气!
祈祷
我们倾其所有
We offer everything we have.
甚至出卖灵魂
We offer up our souls...
只为换取哪怕多一天的时间
in exchangE...for just one more day.
Stevens 你能听见我说话吗?
stevens,can you hear me?
看着我 Stevens
look at me,stevens.
见鬼
damn it.
当交涉失败 愤怒难以控制
When the bargaining has failed  and the anger  is too hard to maintain,
我们陷入消沉
we fall into depression,
绝望
despair,
直到最后不得不承认我们无能为力
until finally we have to accept  that we have done  everything we can.
于是放手
We let go.
放手 最后接受事实
we let go  and move into acceptance.
有谁知道他是不是器官捐赠人?
anybody know if he's a donor?
-=伊甸园美剧 http://sfile.ydy.com=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=- Proudly Presents
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=- 翻译: mmowen 小跑步的熊 蓉蓉 cctv will uu里 马蚤 校对: 蓉蓉 uu里 时间轴: 消 猪 泡 猪二
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=- Sync: YTET -  消 猪 泡 猪二
第1天
DAY ONE
医人当自强 第六季 第1&2集
Season 6  Episode 1&2 Good Mourning & Goodbye
她想取出来 可以拔出来吗?
She wants it out.Can't we take it out?
她能自己呼吸
She's breathing over the vent.
好 拔管
All right. Let's pull out the tube.
Bailey医生
dr. Bailey.
没事的 放松
it's okay.Slow down.
来 放松
Okay,come on.Slow down.
颅内压太高
his I.C.P.Went through the roof.
我们尽力了 尽全力了
We did everything.Everything.
主任 他的器官现在可用 但...
Chief,his organs are viable for now.But ...
但时效不长 不久就会酸中毒且体温下降
it won't be long until he's acidotic and hypothermic.
他是捐献者吗?
Is he a donor?
不清楚
Um,I-I don't know.
我通知了他母亲 她在来的路上
I called his mother.She's on her way.
把他缝合好 安置在重症监护室里 也许他母亲想要见他一面
Let's close him up and get him to the I.C.U.In case she wants  see him.
- 谁...谁是George? - 什么?
- Who--who's george? - What?
无名氏 把我从车前推开的家伙
John doe.The guy who threw me out of the way of the bus.
救我一命的那人
The guy who saved my life.
大家都在哭 说什么"无名氏是George" 谁是George?
Everyone's crying,and they keep saying,"john doe is george." Who's george?
不能告诉她
You can't tell her.
- Alex - 她在我怀里停止呼吸 突然就死了
- Alex - she coded in my arms.Out of nowhere,she died.
就...
Just...
我会告诉她
I'll tell her.
等她再好点 我会告诉她
I'll tell her when she gets stronger.
Alex
Alex.
O'MALLEY参军了
O MALLEY JOINED THE ARMY
感觉还好吗?
You okay?
我做了...
I had...
一个梦
a dream.
- 他穿着军装 - 什么?
- He was in his uniform. - What?
如果我们不拦着他 George会死在军队里
George is gonna die in the army if we don't stop him.
把电话递给我 我要电话
Hand me my phone.I need my phone.
谁说这是George? 凭什么认为这是George?
Who said that was george?Why do we think that's george?
Meredith说...
Meredith said...
我不知道
I don't know.
这不是George
That's not george.
看...看他的脚
Look... look at his feet.
这人个子高着呢
Look how tall he is.
这不是George
That's not george.
他在我手心里写
he wrote in my hand.
- 用笔? - 他什么?
- with a pen? - what did he do?
- 在你手心? - 那是什么...
- in your hand? - What does that
不 他抓过我的手握着 然后用手指写
no,he grabbed my hand and he squeezed it,and he wrote with his finger.
用手指写?
He wrote with his finger?
在我手里 他写了"007"
You know,in my hand.He wrote "007."
把手给我...
We,give... I don't understand.
好 我写了什么?
Okay,what did I write?
Joe?
不!
N-no!
- 不 我写的不是"Joe" - 你在开玩笑吗?
- No,I did not write "joe. - " Are--are you serious?
- Grey 这可能不是O'malley? - 真是搞笑
- Grey,do you mean this may not be o'malley? - This is funny.
有人给O'malley打过电话吗?
did anyone try and call o'malley?
能打通他的电话吗?
Can we get him on the phone?
我告诉你们 他使劲握着我的手
I'm telling you,he squeezed my hand.
闭嘴 什么都别说 以后都不许你说话
Just sh-shut it.You don't get to talk anymore.You don't get to talk ever again.
- 我发誓 那就是George - 只接通语音信箱
- I could've sworn it was george. - I got voice mail.
他没有接听
He's not answering.
他的右手有个雀斑
He has a freckle on his right hand.
形状像德州 我过去总为这个嘲笑他
It's shaped like texas.I used to tease him about it.
我去检查
I'll check.
大家赶紧回呼
you people,answer your pages.
今天George O'malley冲到车前
George o'malley jumped in front of a bus today.
他知道自己在做什么 他无所畏惧地做了
He knew what he was doing,and he did it anyway,
他这样做是为了拯救一条生命
and he did it to save a life.
所以我不允许你们杵在这里
So I'm not gonna allow you doctors to stand here.
有许多人命悬一线
There are lives on the line.
有许多生命我们可以拯救
There are lives we can save.
如果George O'malley能冲到车前
So if george o'malley can jump in front of a bus,
我们也能回复这该死的呼叫
we can answer our damn pages.
去做事吧
So let's go.
该死的 该死 O'malley
damn it.Damn it,o'malley.
疼痛感什么时候开始的?
now how long ago did the pain start?
不确定 几周前吧
I don't know.A-a few weeks?
发育期痛 我带他去看了医生
Growing pains.I took him to see our doctor.
那医生很糟糕
He's a bad doctor.
我跟他说话时 他站在那儿发短信
He's--he stands there texting while I'm talking to him.
他说Andy是发育期痛
He diagnosed andy with growing pains.
但是 我也经历过发育期痛 它不会严重到让你倒在足球场上
But,you know,I grew up,and growing pains did not cause me to fall down on the soccer field.
妈妈 你说得太夸张了
Mom,you're being a little dramatic.
你的疼痛对我来说才夸张呢 Andy
Your pain is dramatic to me,andy.
你妈说得对 你应该来就诊
Your mom's right.It's a good thing that you came.
好的 谢了 因为确实很痛
Okay,thanks,because it does hurt.
每时每刻 每个部位都在痛
Everything hurts,all the time.
好的 给你做个快速检查
Okay.Well,I'm gonna give you a quick exam,
你要告诉我疼痛是否加剧 好吗?
and you're gonna let me know if the pain gets worse,okay?
一切都太不真实了
This doesn't feel real.
你相信这是真的吗?
Does this feel real to you?
不信 我也不知道
No. I don't know.
糟了 我不想...
Oh,crap.I don't want...
- 不要啊 - 别走开 别那样 别...
- I can't - Don't walk away now.Come on.Don't walk... mm.
O'malley太太 我很遗憾
Mrs. O'malley... I'm so sorry.
你曾经是他的妻子
you were his wife.
在上帝眼中 你仍旧是他妻子
In god's eyes,you're still his wife.
应该你来决定他的器官归属
You should decide about his organs.You should decide.
- 但是... - 我做不来 Callie
- But,um - I can't do it,callie.
我做不来
I can't do it.
你能理解吗?
You understand?
Ronnie和Jerry去阿拉斯加 参加什么非法调查了
Ronnie and--and jerry,they're off on some fishing expedition in alaska,
他们回来后 我得告诉他们Georgie...
and they're gonna come home and I have to tell them that georgie...
那是我唯一能做的了
that's all I can do.
那是我唯一... 我做不来
That's all I can... I can'T.
光是看看他现在这个样子我都做不来 我没法决定
I-I can'T... even see him like this.I can'T.
我需要你帮我决定
You need to do this for me.
你能帮帮我吗?
Can you do this for me?
快艇事故
speed boat accident.
19岁 女性
19-year-old female.
两度失去生命体征 但血压保持在低80
Lost vitals twice,but B.P.'S holding in the low 80s.
两只手臂在现场断裂 右腿几乎断裂
Both arms amputated at the scene,and the right leg's hanging on by a thread.
找到任何一只手臂了吗?
Did you recover either of the arms?
没有 它们可能已经沉到普吉湾底了
No,they're probably at the bottom of puget sound.
她飞出快艇 被绞进螺旋桨
She was thrown from the boat,got pulled into the propeller.
她需要更多输液 还在失血
She needs more access.She's bleeding out.
给她插入中心静脉导管 快走
Let's get a central line in her.Let's go.Go.
进行外伤检测 查血配型 尽量多拿些O型阴型血
draw trauma labs,uh,type and cross her and get as much o-neg as possible.
等等!
Wait!
我找到了 她的手臂!
I found them.I found them.Her arms!
她们是跟她一起搭快艇的
they were on the boat with her.
我在水里找到的 你们拿去
I found them in the water.You have to take them.
飘在水面上
They were just floating in the water.
- 你们能把它们接上 是吗? - 我们尽力而为
- You--you can sew them back on,right? - We'll do everything we can.
天哪 JoJo 真恶心
Oh,my god,jojo.That was so gross.
Jasmine 你救了她的命
Jasmine,you just saved her life.
真的吗?
You think?
我很遗憾 我刚听说了
I'm so sorry.I just heard.
不知道该说些什么
I don't know what to say.
回家吧 你需要回家休息
Go home.You need to go home.
需要大哭大叫 尽情宣泄
You need to cry and scream and--
我弟弟去世的时候 我吃甜甜圈
when my brother died,I-I ate doughnuts.
吃了好多甜甜圈 有点作用 但是...
I ate a lot of doughnuts,and that helped some but...
天哪 我不知道怎么安慰你
god,I-I don't know what to say.
他妈妈让我决定他的器官归属
His mom wants me to decide about his organs.
他的钱包在车祸中丢了 无法知道他是不是器官捐献者
He lost his wallet in the accident.They don't know if he's a donor,
现在他妈妈让我来决定 但我做不到
and now his mom wants me to decide,and can'T.
我没法拒绝 但也没法做决定
I can't tell her no,but I can't decide.
我们的婚姻仅仅维持了几个月
I mean,we were only married for a few months.
的确 但是...
Okay,but...
那几个月 你是George生命中最重要的人
during those months,you were the most important person in george's life.
不 我不是
No.No,I wasn'T.
很抱歉 我们来看看X光片吧
- I... I'm sorry. - Okay,so let's take a look at the x-rays.
我需要带儿子换家医院吗?
Do I need to take my son to another hospital?
什么?
What?
那个医生打针时手发抖 护士们都在哭泣
That doctor's hands are shaking as he tries to stick my son with a needle,and those nurses are crying.
你和你的朋友 这到底是怎么一回事?
You and your friend-- what the hell is going on here?
出了场车祸 我们一位同事去世了
There was an accident,and one of our people died.
Andy是我的亲人
andy is my person.
他是我唯一的亲人
He's my only person.
现在...
And...
他生病了
something is wrong with him.
所以我问你 需要带他转院吗?
So what I'm asking you is,do I need to take him somewhere else?
不
No.
不需要
我会把Andy当成自己的亲人 好吗?
I'll make andy my person,okay?
我也会把Andy当作亲人
I'll make andy my person,too.
我没告诉她 行了吧?
I didn't tell her,okay?
Karev
Karev--
我们忽略了她的DNR
look,we just ignored her D.N.R.
她肾脏衰竭 心脏停跳
Her kidneys quit and she coded.
她还插过管呢
She was freaking intubated.
她承受不了
She's not strong enough.
- 血尿素氮多少? - 15
- What's her B.U.N.? - 15.
- 肌氨酸酐呢? - 1.5.
- And her creatinine? - 1.5.
她可以承受的
She's strong enough.
她能够承受的 你必须告诉她
She's strong enough,and you have to tell her.
- 为什么? 可以再等等 - 不行 等不了了
- Why?It can wait. - No,it can'T.
没时间了 George的器官等不了多久
It can't wait because george's organs are not gonna be viable for long.
要用的话 必须趁早 我得决定捐献否
If they want to use 'em,ey have to do it soon,and I have to decide if they get to use 'em,
我要Izzie帮我 她才是该做决定的人
and I need izzie to help me,because she's the one who should decide.
她才是应该决定的人
She's who should decide.
这是原因之一... 还有个原因
So that's one reason and... and the other reason is,
Karev 如果你没让她 在George被拔管前跟他告别
karev,if you let them unplug george without giving her a chance to say good-bye...
她永远不会原谅你 真的
I mean it,she will never forgive you.
你必须告诉她
You have to tell her.
她的血压持续下降
her pressure keeps dropping.
上输液器 进行快速静脉输血
Let's throw in an I.O. And put the blood in the rapid infuser.
伤口很整齐 胳膊可以重新接上
These are pretty clean amputations.We can reattach these arms.
耶!我找到了胳膊 知道不?
Yay!I found 'em,you know?
我在检查网膜 马上送去手术室 快
I'm looking at omentum.Let's get her to an O.R. Now.
你们的朋友有无过敏或病史? 是否在服用任何药物?
Does your friend have any allergies,medical conditions?Is she on any medication?
- 她不是我们的朋友 - Jasmine!
- She's not our friend. - Jasmine!
我们都不太认识她 悉尼坐飞机时才认识
We barely know her.We met her on the plane from sydney.
我们是背包族 环游各州
We're backpacking,seeing the states.
所以不太了解她 驴友而已
So we hardly know her.We're just traveling mates.
但她人真的很好
She's really nice,though.
好 去手术室
all right,let's move.
名字呢 你们知道吗?
A name.Uh,can you give me that?
Clara 我想是Clara...Ferguson
Clara.Clara... ferguson,I think.
Clara Ferguson
Clara ferguson.
Clara 挺住
Clara,hang in there.Stay with me.
她和母亲住在伦敦 她的背包在我车里
She lives with her mum in london.I have her backpack in my car.
- 去拿来 - 我们要留下吗?
- Okay,get it. - Should we stay?
是的 去候诊室 我会及时向你通报最新情况
Yes,uh,in the waiting room.I'll update you when I can.
Shepherd医生
dr. Shepherd.
Jennings先生 很高兴见到你
Mr.Jennings.It's good to see you.
你叫Derek 是不?
It's derek,right?
- 我能直呼你Derek吗? - 当然
- May I call you derek? - Of course.
我听说你刚失去一位住院医生
I understand you lost a resident.
真让人难过 我很遗憾
That's sad.I'm sorry.
医院董事局就要召开大会 Derek
But the hospital board is meeting soon,and,derek,
我想知道你是否愿意成为 西雅图仁爱医院的下一任外科主任
I need to know if you'd like to be the next chief of surgery at seattle grace.
George
George.
是我
it's me.
我刚才差点挂了
You know,I pretty much died not too long ago.
给我回电
So I need you to call me back.
求你了
Please.
我知道
I know.
我搬出癌症那一套 很恶心 但随便了
I played the cancer card.I'm gross.Whatever.
我想告诉你件事 你一定不要慌
I need to tell you something,and I need you to not panic.
保持呼吸
I need you to keep breathing.
我要你活着 因为...
I need you to stay alive,'cause...
我向上帝发誓 我要你活着
I swear to god,I need you to stay alive.
好吗?
All right?
好
Okay.
O'malley...
发生车祸
he got in an accident.
脑部死亡
He's brain dead.
不好意思 你说什么?
I'm sorry.What?
他的心脏呢?
What about his heart?
好
Okay.
眼睛呢?
His eyes?
我知道
I know.
难以想象他没有眼睛的样子
Don't want to imagine him without his eyes.
George会愿意捐出一切
George would give everything.
皮肤 眼睛 他会愿意捐出一切
His skin,his eyes-- he would give everything.
我手上有个孩子
I have a kid in there--
15岁 之前很健康
15 years old,previously healthy--
现在背部疼痛 严重到呕吐的地步
has back pain bad enough to cause vomiting.
能帮我分析一下吗? 我找不出原因 觉得还是探讨一下好
Can you talk it through with me?Because I can't figure out what it is,and I think best out loud.
你难道没听说George O'malley的事?
Did you not hear about george o'malley?
听说了
I did.
难受得让人无法置信
It's incredibly sad.
我现在没法和你谈
I cannot talk to you right now.
现在也工作不了
I cannot work right now.
Bailey医生 我听说了
dr. Bailey... I hear that.
我不是麻木不仁
And I don't mean to be insensitive.
但这个孩子 他还活着啊
But this kid?This kid's still alive.
我不知道他到底怎么了 毫无头绪
And I don't know what's wrong with him.Not a clue.
所以...我要你工作起来
So... I need you to work.
我要你和我分析 这个还没死去的病人的病情 Bailey
I need you to talk through this living patient with me,bailey.
求你了
Please.
他的神经检查结果如何?
how's his neuro exam?
正常
Normal.
会不会是...压迫性骨折?
Could it be... a compression fracture?
平片和CT呈阴性
Plain films and C.T. Are negative.
有无先天不足?
Any congenital problems?
没有
None reported.
- 需要回家吗? - 不需要
- Need to go home? - No.
- 吃饭没? - 没有
- Did you eat? - No.
能吃得下吗?
Can you eat?
吃不下
no.
- 哭过没? - 没
- Did you cry? - No.
- 可能哭出来会好一些 - 我...你只要...你在这儿...
- Maybe if you cried,you'd feel better. - I--you just--just,uh,you being here is...
什么也别说 在这儿陪我 就行
and don't say anything,just be here,that--that--that helps.
你好吗?
how are you?
Meredith 我们需要你
Meredith.We need you.
好的 失陪
Okay.Excuse me.
Amanda 你得离开 我们需要用这个房间
amanda.You have to go.We need the room.
真的对不起
I'm so sorry.
我知道
I know.
对不起 我...
I'm sorry.I'M...
真是对不起
I'm so sorry.
你也这么认为?
you,too,huh?
发育期痛 你说这是发育期痛...
Growing pains.You're saying this is growing p--
不不 不仅仅是发育期痛
no,no,no.Not just growing pains.
他有轻微的脊柱侧凸 连同生长突增
He has a mild case of scoliosis,whh,combined with a growth spurt,
会导致疼痛及球场上的行动迟缓
could account for the pain and the clumsiness on the soccer field.
观察几星期看是否康复
So we'll see if it settles in a couple of weeks,
如果没有 你们还得来再接受检测
and if not,then you'll come back in for more tests.
为什么现在不检测?
Why don't you just run them now?
因为下面的检测需要给Andy脊柱扎针
Because the next set of tests involve things like sticking large needles into andy's spine.
太好了 那我们回家
All right,then.Heading home.
你对此能肯定吗?
You're sure about this?
不
No.
但我能给你开些肌肉松弛剂
But I'm gonna write a prescription for muscle relaxants,
有情况 我随时都在这里 希望没有
and you know that I'm here if you need me,which I really hope that you won'T.
O'malley的事 Torres决定了吗?
Did torres decide about o'malley?
- 器官捐献? - 我不知道
- About his organs? - I don't know.
我去看一下
I'm gonna see where they are.
头儿
Uh,chief.
我知道 这是个糟到不能再糟的时机
Look,I... I know this is the worst possible moment,
但是...我们得谈谈
but...  we need to talk.
董事局正在策划变动
The board is planning a coup.
他们说你失职
They're saying that you dropped the ball,
致使医院排名没有上升
that our ranng isn't coming up.
他们想撤你的职
They want to oust you.
他们希望我支持这个决定
They're asking me to support it.
他们希望我站出来 顶上这个位子
They're asking me to step up,to take the job.
我的位子?
Take my job?
我说我要考虑一下
I told them I'd think about it.
以此帮你争取时间 但你得有应对计划
I bought you some time.But you need a plan.
Torres做决定了
torres has made a decision.
你是要报告快艇女的最新情况吗?
Were you here to give an update on the boating victim?
是了 她们在...
Uh,yeah.Where are--
她们走了 她的朋友们走了
they left.Her friends left.
她们说要赶飞机 不想错过 在拉斯维加斯的一个什么音乐会
They saithat they hada plane to catch and something about a concert in vegas that they didn't want to miss.
- 她们留下了她的包 - 这个手术如成功 后面还有一连串手术
- They left her pack for you. - She's got dozens of surgeries ahead of her,if she survives this one.
她需要一个支持团队
She needs a support system.
这样吧 在联系到她家人前 你当她的家人 记好了
Okay,until we find her family,you're it.Keep that.
不...不好意思
Uh,w--I'm--I'm sorry.
你希望...你命令我做她的朋友?
You want me-- you--you're ordering me to what,be her friend?
她将在剧痛中醒来 少了一条腿 胳膊还不能动
She's gonna wake up in a lot of pain missing one of her legs and unable to use either of her arms,
所以 是的 我命令你做她朋友 因为我肯定做不来
so yes,I am ordering u to be her friend,'cause I'm sure as hell not gonna do it.
我要回去手术了
I'm heading back to surgery.
病人是George O'malley 29岁
patient is george o'malley,29.
程序是分离捐献器官
Procedure is organ recovery for donation.
我会依次叫受捐者的医生
I will call on the receiving surgeons.
肾
Kidneys.
St.Luke儿童医院
St.Luke's children'S.
- 博伊西市 - 受捐者是谁?
- Boise. - Who is it for?
什么?
Sorry?
他的肾是给谁?
Who are his kidneys for?
- 护士会回答你 - 我希望你告诉我
- I gave all that to the nurse. - I would like you to tell me.
Molly Kemper 8岁 肾发育不良
Molly kemper... 8 years old,hypoplastic kidneys.
谢谢
thank you.
肺?
Lungs?
肺和心脏将运往波特兰中心医院
Lungs and heart are going to portland medical center.
Terry Class 22岁
Terry class,age 22.
囊肿性纤维化
Cystic fibrosis.
肝?
Liver?
第7天
***
你太邪恶了 你是魔鬼
you are ev.You are the devil.
是的 我不否认
I am. I admit it.
Cristina 你很清楚规矩的
Cristina,you know the rules.
愚蠢的规矩
Oh,the rules are stupid.
你是说我的心理医生很蠢?
So you're saying my shrink's stupid?Hmm?
我说她是个假正经
I'm saying she's a prude.
她假正经 而且理解错了
She's prudey and--and misguided.
她想让我们了解对方
She wants us to get to know each other.
她想让我不断地认识自己
She wants me to keep getting to know myself.
她不想让我因为你而放弃自我
She does not want me... burying myself in you.
如果我们发生关系 我会放弃自我 (字面意思: 拜倒在你的体内)
And if we start to have sex... I'll bury myself in you.
现在轮到谁邪恶了?
Oh,now who's evil?
这不会持续很久的
It's not gonna be too much longer.
你想让我放弃心理治疗么?
You want me to quit therapy? Hmm?
不是 真烦人
No!Crap.
明天要去参加O'malley的葬礼
All right.We have to go to o'malley's funeral anyway.
我讨厌葬礼 还是别去了
No,I hate funerals.Let's skip it.
我们可以提前做酸橘汁腌鱼的清创手术 这是个很好的借口
Uh,we can,uh,push up ceviche's debridemen that's good excuse.
- 酸橘汁腌鱼? - 就是剁碎了的鱼
- Ceviche? - Chopped up fish.
被绞进螺旋桨的那个 人就像剁碎的腌鱼 好好笑
Propeller accident.Ceviche.It's funny.
好变态才对
Right.It's sick.
- 所以才好笑 - 我们一定要去葬礼
- That's what makes it funny. - We are going to the funeral.Come on.
然后骑单轮车身背翅膀的男孩 把我们带到平台上
"And then all these unicycle boys with wings "carried us on a platform like we were cleopatra or something.Hilarious.
就像我们是埃及艳后之类的 好玩得要命
真不敢相信她们去了火人节
" I can't believe they went to burning man.
母夜叉
Hags.
她们之前都没听说过火人节
They'd never even heard of burning man.
我恨她们
I hate them.
Clara 忘了她们吧
Clara... forget them.
好不好? 她们脑残
Okay?They're morons.
她们只是... 想想今天
They're just... think about today.
事实上 今天将有可能进行 你的最后一次清创手术
Okay,the fact that today,you're gonna get what we believe is your final debridement,
之后 理疗师会帮你恢复手臂运动
and then after that,we're gonna get the physical therapist in here to get your arm moving.
所以我把这张留给你以后自己撕
So I am gonna save this piece for you to do.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 现在我再问你一次 - 不
- Now I'm gonna ask you one more time. - No.
- 你不想打电话给你妈妈吗? - 不
- Don't you want to call your mom... - no.
在你下次手术之前?
Before your next surgery?
不 还没到时候
No. Not yet.
但我们可以再给她写封电邮
But we could write her another e-mail.
会耽误你出席葬礼么?
Will it make you late for your funeral?
不会
No,no.
"妈妈您好 希望您身体健康"
***I hope you're well.
"除热浪和异味之外  火人节真的让人惊喜"
Aside from the heat and the smell,burning man was amazing.
凡事都有定期 天下万物都有定时
there is an appointed time for everything,and a time for every affair under the heavens...
生有时 死有时  栽种有时 拔出所栽种的也有时
a time to be born and a time to die,a time to plant and a time to uproot the plant,
杀戮有时 医治有时 拆毁有时 建造有时
a time to kill and a time to heal... a time to tear down and a time to build...
你还好吧?
are you okay?
- 哭有时... - 你要坐轮椅么?
- A time to weep... - you want the wheelchair?
笑有时 哀恸有时 跳舞有时
And a time to laugh,a time to mourn and a time to dance,
抛掷石头有时 堆聚石头有时
a time to cast away stones and a time to gather stones together,
怀抱有时 不怀抱有时
a time to embrace,and a time to refrain from embracing.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你在笑?
You're laughing?
她在笑
She'laughing.
George...George死了
george--george is dead.
他死了
He's dead.
他要下葬了 牧师却在念经典的摇滚乐歌词
They're about to put him in the ground,and the priest is doing classic rock lyrics.
那个红毛丫头 比他老妈哭得还厉害 她根本就没见过他
And that girl,that redhead is crying harder than his mother,and she never even met him.
- 只是.. - 我从没意识到你这么变态
- It's just... - you are far more twisted than I ever realized.
你贴个即时贴就结婚了
and you got married on a post-it.
我是贴个即时贴就结婚了 没错
I got married on a post-it.I did. I did.
你们俩是真的结婚?
You know,you guys got married for real?
就是!
I know!
还有 我得了癌症
and I got cancer.
什么?
What?
O'malley被车撞了
Dude,o-o'malley got hit by a bus.
噢 天哪
oh,my god.
她哭个不停
she never stops crying.
不是时候 拜托 现在不是时候
not now. Please not now.
一周了 你一直在回避我
It's been a week.You've been avoiding me.
现在不谈这个
Not now.
我在为你争取时间 你知道吗?
I am buying you time,you know?
我在为你争取时间
I am buying you time.
你不知道我付出了多少
You have no idea what I've given.
你不知道我作出了怎样的牺牲
You have no idea what I have sacrificed.
每次失算的背后 都有上百次的贡献
For every miscalculation you think u see,there have been a hundred things
但是没人知道
that I have gotten right,and no one knows.
我是站在你这边的 不是吗?
Look,I'm on your side,okay?
我不是董事会成员 我不是Jennings
I'm--I'm not the board.I'm not jennings.
那就别来烦我
Well,then back off,then.
别来烦我 给我时间想想
Just back off and... you give me time to think.
给我点时间 O'malley是我的实习生
Let me have a minute to... o'malley was my intern.
我只想花一点点时间
And I am trying to just take a minute.
Derek 求你了
So,derek,please...
别来烦我
back off.
要我载你回去么?
you want a ride home?
我本来想清理他的储物柜 把他的遗物给他妈妈 但...
I s gonna clean ous locker,give his stuff to his mom,but...
我不配做George的朋友
I was a bad friend to george.
我对他就像Clara的朋友对她一样 给她送旅行明信片 而她却永远去不了了
I was about as good a friend to him as clara's friends,who keep sending postcards from the trip that she'll never get to take.
我只是... 我完全抛弃了他
I just... I... I abandoned him completely.
我搬了出来 再也不和他说话 为啥呢?
I-I-I just... moved out and--and stopped talking to him and... why?
因为我认为他帅 他却不觉得我漂亮
Because--because he didn't thini was as hot as I thought he was or be-because he--he didn't--
因为他没有回报我的爱?
he didn't love me back?
现在也许不该问这个问题 但我还是想问
This... may be bad timing,but I gotta ask.
他好在哪里?
What did that guy have?
我是说 他长得不咋的
I mean,he wasn't much to look at.
但你 Stevens和Torres都对他死心塌地?
But you and stevens and torres?
说实话
Tell the truth.
他...那里很雄壮么?
Was he... you know... hung?
- 这... - 我知道 现在不该问
- That's-- I know.I said bad timing.
- 我... - 说真的 他就是个傻小子
- I-- but seriously,he was kind of a dorky little dude.
别说了
Stop.Stop talking.
对不起 对不起
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
他死了
he... he died.
我... George死了
I... george died.
是啊
Yeah.
第10天
***
好 这里疼吗?
Okay,any pain here?
现在深呼吸
Now take a deep breath.
站起来时眩晕么? 深呼吸
Any dizziness when you stood up?Take a deep breath.
- 不 - 好的
no. okay.
你回家吧
You are going home.
12天以后再回来 再用白介素2治疗一个疗程
You are gonna come back in 12 days for another round of I.L.-2,
治疗以后两周再来做正子造影
and then you have your pet-scan two weeks after that.
你不必再躺在病床上了
But there's no need for you to keep living in this bed.
放轻松点
You should take it easy.
你还是癌症病人 但不用再做手术了
You're still a cancer patient,but you're no longer a surgical patient.
谢谢 Bailey医生
Thank you,dr. Bailey.
我不知道怎么感谢您
I don't know how to... thank you.
出院前别忘了填写出院文件
Uh,don't forget to sign the discharge papers before you leave.
Andy?
他的腹股沟处 腿根部和下背部剧痛
He's got serious pain in his inguinal area and down his legs and in his lower back.
体温101度 他妈妈说他整晚呕吐
He's got a temp of 101,and his mom says he's been throwing up all night.
请别告诉我这是发育期痛 Robbins医生
Please don't tell me this is growing pains,dr. Robbins.
我做不来
I can't do it.
没关系
It's okay.
手一点都不能动
I can't move it at all.
手术做完才三天
it's only been three days since your last surgery.
肿会消的 深呼吸 你恢复得不错
The swelling will come down.Take a deep breath.You're doing great.
是的 不错
Right. Great.
我们上次写到哪了 大峡谷?
So... where did we leave off,at the grand canyon?
是的
Yeah.
写到"辽阔雄伟的峡谷"
Big,gorgeous hole in the ground.
好的 "很想您 妈妈"
Okay,uh,miss you,mum.
"希望您也能目睹"
uh,wish you could see it.
Clara 打断一下
Clara,sorry.
你恢复得不错 但还要在这里治很久
Um... you are doing great,but you got a long road here.
相信我 你妈妈想知道这一切
And believe me,your mom,she's gonna want to know.
她会想帮你的
And she's gonna want to help.
她把我从小拉扯大
She madee from scratch.
她总是这么说
That's what she always says.
就像 我想去跳伞的时候
Like... when I wanted to go skydivando salt?
"别跳出飞机 Clara"
"don't jump out of a plane,clara.
"你那身体是我从小拉扯大的"
I made that body from scratch.
我扭伤了踝关节 "小心点 亲爱的"
" Or when I sprained my ankle... "be more careful,darling.
"那脚踝是我从小拉扯大的"
I made that ankle from scratch.
"想念您 妈妈"
" Miss you,mum.
"我很好"
I'm doing great.
"爱您的Clara"
love you.Clara.
进来
come i
Torres医生
oh,dr. Torres.
头儿 我只是想知道
Chief,I was just,um... I was just wondering.
我申请主治医生 但没收到任何回应 所以...
I,um,haven't heard anything about my application for attending,so...
Torres医生 Chang医生的401K退休金 没申请到 推迟一两年退休
well,dr. Torres,dr. Chang's 401(k) took a hit,and he's putting off retirement for another year or two.
所以 你不准备给我这个工作?
So... so wait.You're not giving me the job?
没有岗位了 今年没有了
There is no job,not this year.
抱歉 我以为你已经听说了
I'm sorry.I assumed you'd heard.
Chang医生只是个花瓶罢了 你清楚的 对不对?
Okay,um,dr. Chang is basically a figurehead.You're clear on that,right?
他们需要最好的医生时 都会呼我
When people want the best,they page me.
基本是我在常年维持Chang医生的部门
I have basically been running dr. Chang's department all year.
- Chang医生无不良记录 - 他老得都成化石了!
- dr. Chang has an impeccable record. - He is a dinosaur!
我也是!
And so am I!
你... 这太疯... 你会后悔的
You're...  this is c-- you're gonna regret this.
- Torres医生 - 不 不
- dr. Torres-- no,no,no.
我只是...不
I am just...  no.
我很棒
I am excellent.
任何其他医院能请到我都会高兴得发狂
I am excellent,and any other hospital would be thrilled to have me.
你们的建议让我受宠若惊 Larry  我在认真考虑
I'm flattered for the offer,larry,and I'm seriously considering it
但是 事情没那么简单 给我点时间
but it's-- it's complicated,and I need a little more time.
不能再给你时间了 Derek
I can't give you more time,derek.
我可以给你钱 好处 抛头露面的机会
I can give you more money,better benefits and a whole lot of press--
这些都可以
that's what I can give you.
但我给不了你更多的时间
But I can't give you much more time.
是的 我就是
Yes,I am.
我是天后级别 手术天后
I'm a superstar-- a superstar with a scalpel.
- Torres - 别! 别叫我
- Torres-- no!Don't say my name.Do not.
我是天后 你不配叫我的名字
I am too big a star for you to say my name.
我能凭空造出四肢 像神一样
I build arms out of nothing,and legs,like god.
当我得了哈伯之类的奖项时 Webber主任 你会懊悔这一天的
And when I win the harper avery and every other prize there is,you will rue this day,chief webber.
是的
That's right.
我说了 懊悔
I said "rue.
管得真严啊 Webber
" Tight ship you're running here,webber.
纪律严明啊
Al tight ship.
第11天
Amanda
Amanda.
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
我...睡不着
Uh,I... can't sleep.
我睡不着 因为我总看见他的脸
I can'T... fall asleep 'cause I see his face all the time.
我看见他在车站 甜甜的 微笑着
I see him at the bus stop... you know,sweet,smiling,and then...
然后我看见他变成那样 他最好的朋友都认不出来 我睡不着
and then I see the way that he ended up,so that even his best friends can't recognize him,and I can't sleep.
你睡得着么?
Can you... can you sleep?
我...给你开点抗焦虑的药
I,um... am gonna write you a prescription for an antianxiety medication.
希望你能服用 失眠对身体害处很大
And I want you to take it,because this sleep deprivation thing can be quite harmful.
- Robbins医生 - 主任
- dr. Robbins. - Chief.
你给病人预定了紧急三维核磁共振?
Did you order an emergent 3-d M.R.I. For this patient?
好吧 你很生气 我能看得出
Okay,you're mad.I see that.
但是以他妈妈的医保 得等上几周才能做核磁共振
But with the patient's mother's insurance,it could take weeks to get an M.R.I.
而且疼痛专科转诊...
And a specialty pain referral--
那你让谁来给医院买单呢?
so you expect the hospital to pay for this with whose money?
- 头儿 我只是想... - 我不想听 Robbins医生
- Oh,well,sir,I only thought that-- I don't want to hear it,dr. Robbins.
让病人出院 让他再去找内科医生 赶紧
Now discharge your patient,refer him back to his physician,and do it now.
Karev医生  计划有变
dr. Karev,change of plans.
第13天
***
开门!
open up!
开门 Torres
Open the door,torres.
开门 否则我一直敲下去 有可能会伤到我这价值几百万的双手哦
Open the door or I'll keep knocking and potentially damage my multimillion-dollar hands.
我的前夫死了
my ex-husband died.
他死了
He died.
他真的被车撞了
He actually got hit by a bus.
George被车撞了
George got hit by a bus.
现在我要去找新工作  再也见不到朋友们了
And now--now I have to get a new job,and--and I'm never gonna see my friends anymore.
Arizona不停地给我送甜甜圈
And arizona keeps bringing me doughnuts.
we'll set up the scaffolding here.
这房子要卖? 真不赖
this place for sale?It's nice.
什么?
what?
没事 没事
Oh,nothing,nothing.
噢 天!
oh,my god!
Derek!
老兄 开房去啊
dude,get a room.
在楼梯上? 不疼么?
On the stairs?Doesn't that hurt?
别管我们 我们是新婚夫妇!
leave us alone.We're newlyweds!
就是个即时贴婚礼 你们谈不上新婚
A post-it wedding does not make you newlyweds.
知道吗? 你们也是新婚啊
You know what?You're newlyweds,too.
你们需要自己的空间
You need your own space.
嘿 老兄 这是什么?
Hey,dude,what are these?
我房车的钥匙 你们的新家 祝愉快
The keys to my trailer-- your new home. Enjoy.
- 是Hunt医生吗? - 是的
- dr. Hunt? - Yes.
我是Louise O'malley
I'm louise o'malley.
George的妈妈
George's mother.
噢对 很抱歉 之前没有...
Of course,of course.I'm sorry.I-I didn'T... I'm sorry.
没关系
It's all right.
希望你别介意我来找你
I'M... i--well,I hope you don't,uh,mh,mind me coming here to see you.
我知道你们外科医生是很忙的
I know you surgeons are--are very busy people.
- 我的Gorgie总是这么说 - 不要紧
- My georgie was always saying-- it's no problem.
没关系
It's fine.
我有个困扰
I'M... Having trouble.
我有个困扰 我...
I'm having trouble... I...
我...无法理解
and I-I-I think it's because I--I'm having trouble understanding.
拼不出完整的答案
Uh,there's a piece of the puzzle missing.
等我理解后 感觉才会好一些
I-I do better when I understand things,how things happen.
George 我的George
And george... my george...
我生他养他 了解他 我的孩子是永远不会去参军的
the boy I knew,the boy I raised,my boy would never have joined the army.
所以我想弄明白
So I'm trying to understand.
我想弄明白这个谜
I'm trying to understand that piece of it.
我想弄清楚Georgie那天为什么没上班
I--I'm trying to understand why georgie wasn't at work that day,
而是要来我家 通知我他要去参军
why he was on his way to my house to tell me he'd joined the army in wartime.
我理会不了
I don't understand.
Webber医生说我该和你谈谈
And dr. Webber said I should talto you.
O'malley太太 我不像您那么了解他
mrs. O'malley,I didn't know him like you knew him.
我认识他不久 但是他作为创伤外科医师很有潜力
I didn't know him long,but he had tremendous potential as a trauma surgeon.
他腿脚麻利  在巨大压力下能头脑清醒立即行动
He... he was very fast on his feet,and he could think and act simultaneously under intense pressure.
他非常有潜力
He had tremendous potential.
而且 你知道 他非常急切
And...  you know,he was impatient.
想迅速进步
He wanted to become better faster.
想挽救更多生命
He wanted to save more lives.
他很优秀
He was good.
善解人意 慷慨无私
And he was thoughtful and generous.
我认为 他是个英雄 品行高尚
And I think in the end,I think... I think he was heroic and noble.
我很喜欢他
And I liked him very much.
你应该为他所做的一切感到自豪
And I think he gave you good reason to be very,very proud.
我要下班了 过来说声晚安的
I'm,uh,headed out.I just wanted to say goodnight.
晚安
Night.
Clara 你刚刚...手指动了
Clara,you just moved-- you moved your fingers.
好像挥手道别一样
Like--like you waved.You waved good-bye.
很了不起啊
This is huge.
这就是了不起?
That's huge?
我就是动了动手?
That I waved?
摇了摇指头?
That I waved a finger?
这就是我以后的生活?
That'S... that's my life from now on?
这就是我最大的希望?
That's the best I have to hope for?
Clara 你看见外面那个 和Hunt医生谈话的女士了吗?
clara... do you see that woman out there talking to dr. Hunt?
她儿子这周刚下葬
We--we buried her son this week.
他和你一样 遇上了事故
He had an accident,like you.
他的身体状况比你还好些 但是他死了
He--he wasn't even as bad off as you were,and he didn't make it.
Clara 我知道这么说你不信 但是你活下来是奇迹
Clara,i know that it doesn't feel like it,but it is a miracle that you lived.
这是个奇迹
It is a miracle.
所以你该给你妈妈电话
So you should call your mom.
她想知道真相
She would want to know the truth.
你这个愚蠢的小贱货
you stupid little bitch.
你真的不了解 对吗?
You really don't get i do you?
你应该让我死
You shoulda let me die.
不关你的事
You had no business.
我只有一只手能动
I've got one working hand.
也许再也不能走路
I may never walk again.
你以为你是上帝?
Do you think you're god?
根本就与你无关
You had no business.
你的朋友那样更好
Your friend is better off.
他妈妈那样更好
His mum is better off.
你认为这是个奇迹?
Do you think this  is a miracle?
谁愿意这样活下去?
Who wants to live like this?
让我死
Just let me die.
让我死!
Just let me die!
- 求求你让我死了吧 - Clara Clara 别这样
- Please just let me die. - clara,clara,you need to stop.
- Clara... - 让我死吧 放开我
- Clara,you need-- just let me die!Get off .
Clara... 我需要帮助!
Clara--I need some help in here!
让我死 让我死
Let me die. Let me die.
别这样 Clara 别乱动
Stop.Clara,stop.You have to stop moving.
在医学院里  上百堂课教我们如何对付死亡
in medical school,we have a hundred classes that teach us  how to fight off death...
但没有一堂课 教会我们如何活下去
and not one lesson  in how to go on living.
The water   yes,my god's gonna trouble   the water  captioned by closed captioning services,inc.
-=伊甸园美剧 http://sfile.ydy.com=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=- Proudly Presents
第20天
********
字典对悲痛的解释是 "因丧失和苦恼而造成的 严重的精神创伤或压力"
the dictionary  defines grief as,"keen mental suffering  or distress  "over affliction or loss.
"剧烈的悲痛"
"Sharp sorrow.
"痛心的懊悔"
Painful regret.
作为医生和科学家 我们一直被教导 要遵循书本 定律与命数
"  As surgeons,as scientists,we're taught to learn from  and rely on books,on definitions,on definitives.
但现实生活中 条条框框几乎没用
But in life...  strict definitions  rarely apply.
生活中 哀伤不仅表现为剧烈的悲痛
In life...  grief can look like  a lot of things  that bear little resemblance  to sharp sorrow.
第21天
*******
"你也没错过什么"
"You're not missing much.
"纽约这城就一股骚味"
New york smells like pee.
天 我恨死她们了
" God,I hate them.
还痛?
more pain?
你CT结果很快就会出来
Your C.T. Results should be back soon.
我没事
I'm fine.
今晚你应该回家
You should go home tonight.
不用24小时盯着我 怕我自杀
You can call off the 24-hour suicide watch,you know?
说真的 我好多了
Honestly,I'm better now.
真的
I am.
知道我是怎么想的吗?
Do you know what I think?
我觉得你是利用我 借此不搬去跟男友同居
I think you're using me to avoid moving in with your boyfriend.
才不是呢
am not.
要不这样 你搬去和男友住 我让你通知我妈
I'll make you a deal-- you move in with your boyfriend,and I'll let you call my mum.
够狠
Oh,mean.
胆小鬼
Chicken.
Clara 你的CT结果显示 小肠感染 而且结肠发炎
okay,uh,clara,the C.T. Shows you have an infection in your small bowel and your colon is inflamed.
应该是你在水上感染到的
It's most likely something you picked up in the water.
已经化脓 也就是说 你需要马上手术
But it seems to have formed an abscess,which means you need surgery right away.
不要
No.
- 如果不做... - 不要
- Uh,if we don't go--  - no.
不要再动手术 我再也不要被人剖开了
No more surgery.I'm not being cut open again.
- 好吧 呃... - 不要
- Okay,uh--  - no.
给你点时间 好好考虑一下
You just take a minute.Take a few minutes.
我等下回来 到时再说
And I'll come back,and we'll discuss it.
给她打术前抗生素 预定手术室
um,start her on pre-op antibiotics and book an O.R.
还有别的选择不? 能只吃药不? 能...
What are the options?Can you givee drugs?Can you--
不行 你要动手术 很简单的手术
no,you need surgery,but it's a simple procedure.
如果顺利 你就会...
And if it all goes as planned,you sh--
我那快艇就没那么顺利
well,my boat de didn't exactly go as planned.
跟我说 最坏的情况会怎样
So tell me,worst case.
最坏的情况是...
Well,uh,worst case is...
我们要剪掉一段结肠 接上结肠瘘袋
that we'd have to take out a part of your colon and give you a colostomy bag--
结肠瘘袋?
colostomy bag?
体外粪袋? 我爷爷就有一个 那真是...
A pooh bag outside your body?My granddad had one of those.It was--
只有很小很小的可能性
no,but it--it's a small,small possibility.
不要粪袋 不要手术 不要
No pooh bag.No surgeryno.
- 感染会要了你的命 Clara - 不要
- The infection will kill you,clara  - no.
别再要我动手术了
No more surgery.
我们开了止痛药 按照肾盂肾炎治疗
We tried pain meds and treated him for pyelonephritis.
但有可能是更严重的病情 所以又做了个膀胱内压测量图
But it looks like it could be something more serious,so we did a C.M.G.
就因为尿道 你做了膀胱内压测量图?
You did a C.M.G.For a U.T.I.?
- 你怎么会以为... - 因为没其他主意了
- Why would you even look for something--  - because we were out of ideas.
膀胱内压测量图结果呈阴性 所以可能是神经引起的
The C.M.G. Was negative.So we went back to a possible neurological cause.
如果你授权三维核磁共振  病情就能更清楚了
So if we could get a better look,if you could give us permission to get a 3-d M.R.I.,
- 我们可以... 只是可能... - 主任 这孩子三个星期内看了4次急诊
- We could maybe,just possibly--  - chief,this kid's been in the E.R.Four times in the last three weeks
因为止痛药不起作用
because the pain meds aren't working.
- 为什么不能... - 5000美元 Karev
- Why can't we just-- sir? - $5,000,karev.
不管你跟Robbin医生想啥办法 得把这钱给我
That's how much either you or dr. Robbins would have to put up to cover that scan.
否则 今天下午你跟我去董事会
Otherwise,you could come with me to my board meeting this afternoon
解释你把这家医院当慈善机构来开
and explain why you're running this hospital like it's a charity.
不是吧 这就哭?
dude,are you crying?
我惧怕权威
I have authority issues.
快闪 Karev
walk away,karev.
- 你怎么才能不谋杀我的病人 Yang? - 谋杀你...
- Where do you get off killing my patients,yang? - Killing your--
你自作主张叫那女孩不要做救命手术 你就是在谋杀她
when you take it upon yourself to talk that girl out of a lifesaving surgery,you're killing her.
我没有让她不做 她对手术有疑问
I didn't talk her... she had questions about the surgery.
你当时离开了
You left the room.
我离开是为了让脆弱抓狂的病人 有时间跟空间考虑接受手术
No,I left the room to give a very fragile,very distraught patient time and space to accept what's being asked of her.
只有接受后 我才会告诉她手术的潜在风险
Then and only then would I have discussed the possible risks with,
我敢保证 比你一直以来的做法 更得体更仁慈
I'm certain,more tact and sensitivity than you have ever displayed in all the time that I've known you.
- 她问了... - 她问什么不关我事
- She asked--  - no.I don't care what she ahe asked you.
如果她再问你任何问题 你只能说 "我得去问问主治医师"
And if s asks you anything else,your only answer will be,"let me ask my attending.
第22天
*******
真好吃 餐厅有卖吗?
" These are good.Do they sell these in the cafeteria?
不卖
no.
不对 那是给癌症病人的冰棒
No,those are the cancer pops.
怎么好事都被癌症病人给占了?
Why do cancer people get all the fun?
你感觉怎样了?
How do you feel,iz?
我不指望一下子就好 不过我感觉良好
I'm not looking forward to the hurling that's about to happen,but I feel okay.I feel good.
Bailey发飙了
Bailey's on some sort of rampage.
应该是O'Malley的事带来的功能紊乱
I think it's post-o'malley stress disorder.
她不知道如何处理悲痛
she's not dealing with her grief.
你听着像Owen的心理医生
You sound like owen's shrink.
Owen的心理医生不让他们嘿咻 所以她这么暴躁反常
Owen's shrink... is withholding sex,so she is grumpy and inappropriate.
Derek也是这样? 忍着不做爱?
Is derek doing that,too,withholding sex?
Derek干嘛要忍着?
Why would derek withhold sex?
Alex就在忍着 什么都在忍着
Alex is withholding... everything.
好像是在害怕 但我不知道他怕什么
It's like he's afraid,but i don't know what he's afraid of.
他怕跟癌症病人做爱
He's afraid of the cancer sex.
- Cristina! - 他不想后半辈子都吃癌症冰棒
- Cristina! - He doesn't want to end up with a cancer pop.
- Cristina! - 闭上你臭嘴吧
- Cristina! - Just shut the hell up.
我又不传染 Cristina
I'm not contagious,cristina.
我知道啊
I know that.
换作我 就愿意跟你做爱
I would totally have sex with you.
真的?
really?
什么都不带?
Nothing?
连个抽屉也不带?
You don't even want a drawer?
不带
no.
那牙刷咧? 换洗内裤?
How about a toothbrush,change of panties?
- 不带 - 靠
- No. - Damn.
我爱死你的小裤裤了
I like your panties.
我在整理思绪
I am trying to focus.
今天我就是住院医师了
I'm--I'm becoming a resident today.
我要集中注意力
I need to focus.
我就住在那医院对面
I'm right across the street from the hospital.
如果你和我住 你能参加的手术会翻几番呢
If you crash here sometimes,you'll get a jump on a lot of surgeries.
好了好了
Okay,okay.
哪件好? 我今天第一天在西慈上班 要打扮得漂漂亮亮
Which one?It's my first day at mercy west,and I want to look nice.
要给人认真能干坚强的印象 而不是任人摆布的人
You know,seous,talented,hard-core,not someone you push around.
好看又性感 就象我自身一样
Nice but hot... like me.
那件
That one.
真的? 我还以为这件好
Really?I thought this one.
太性感 约会的时候穿合适 穿那件
Too hot.Better for a date.That one.
好 给你 你能... 谢谢了
Okay. Here.Can you--thanks.
好了
okay. Okay.
- 没那么性感了? - 没那么性感了
-Less hot?  - Less hot.
好了 不错 谢谢
Okay.okay,okay.Good. Thanks.
祝我好运吧
Wish me luck.
或者不用 反正我那么能干坚强
Or not luck,'cause I'm all talented and hard-core.
你是个主治医师了 Torres 好好去耍威风吧
You're an attending,torres.Go kick some ass.
那 呃...
so,um...
你是不是忘了说 你那惹火坚强的 前任性伴侣就住你对面?
did you forget to mention that your hot,hard-core ex-sex-friend lives right across the hall?
我没说?
Did I?
是啊 没说
Yeah,you did.
也只有在我做主任的这任期 西雅图仁爱医院才发展成为名声最响
And it is only under my tenure as chief that seattle grace has grown into one of the most renowned,
最令人称道 最吃香的外科中心之一
lauded and sought-after surgical centers in the country.
想撤我... 不行
Replacing me... no.
否则只会造成巨大错误
Disrupting that process would be an epic mistake.
也是因为这样 今天我才站在这里 信心十足地说
It is for that reason that I stand before you today and say with the utmost confidence
没有人比我更了解更关心仁爱医院
that there is no one who understands and cares more about seattle grace than... than me.
太小题大做了 我没事
look,this is ridiculous.I'm fine.
只是扭了下脚 我还要去开会
It's a sprained ankle,and--and I have a meeting I have to get to.
我都说我没事了
Look,I said I'm fine.
- 主任? - Torres 谢天谢地
- Chief? - Torres.Thank god.
你出车祸了?
You were in a car accident?
小事一桩 我闯红灯了 分了下神
Oh,it was minor.I ran a red light.I was distracted.
我没事
I am fine.
能速战速决不?
Can we make this quick?
我要去参加董事会议
I have a meeting with the board.
好
Okay.
我看看
Let's see.
我也不清楚 这伤口看着满深的
Ooh,I don't know,sir.This lac looks pretty deep.
肯定要缝上几针 还有脚踝 不妙啊
You'll definitely need stitches.and the ankle--oh,yikes.
搞不好还要动手术
Yeah.You could need surgery.
只是扭伤 Torres
It's--it's a sprain,torres.
你们认识?
you two know each other?
Webber医生跟我可有历史了 算起来也一起工作有五六年了
dr. Webber and i go way back,huh we worked together for,what was it,five,six years?
我也不想的 不过你这伤口要好好处理下
You know,I hate to say it,but you're gonna have to have that lac repaired.
再加上这是所教学医院 而且Mckee医生 是第一天上班 我得让他帮你
and this being a teaching hospital,not to mention dr. Mckee's first day,I have to let him work you up.
缝合你会的吧 Mckee医生?
So you know how to do sutures,right,dr. Mckee?
可熟练了
Damn straight.
很好
Great.
很高兴见到你 主任
Good seeing you,chief.
医...
Look,doc--d--
她说这是我第一天 是在说笑呢
she's,uh,she's just kidding about this being my first day.
已经是...第八天了
It's,uh,it's my eighth.
你要用什么线?
What kind of sutures are you using?
- 3号尼龙线? - 不对
- Uh,3-0 nylon? - No,no,no.
用皮肤粘合剂 时间短 愈合快
Use dermabond.It takes less time and it heals quicker.
我也知道 可没那么多预算
Yeah,I know,but,like,budget cuts,you know?
你喜欢在这上班吗 Mckee医生?
you like working in this place,doctor,um,mckee?
你认为这是个很好的团队?
I mean,you think it's a strong program?
爱死了 第八天就能独立做手术
Yeahit rocks.Like,day eight,and I'm doing unsupervised procedures?
差不到哪去
Not too shabby.
第23天
*****
他在西北大学及哈佛大学学习过
Uh,he trained at northwestern and then at harvard.
就在这附近长大
Uh,he grew up like five miles away from here.
小康家庭 有足够的亲情
Um,not rich,not poor.Comfortable and well-loved by his parents,
他急切地想要创造人生
but,um,uh,itching to do something more with his life,
所以申请入伍 当时年龄是...
which is when he enlisted,at the age of--
Cristina 不是叫你交读书报告
cristina,this is not a book report.
我只是想告诉Wyatt医生我了解你
I'm trying to explain to dr. Wyatt that I know things about you.
- Cristina... - 等等
- Cristina--  - wait,wait,wait.
他也知道我的事 如果你是想说这话 我们有聊过的
He knows things about me,too,if thas what you're gonna say,'cause we talk.
我们一直都在交流
I mean,we talk all the time.
亲爱的?
Honey?
"honey"?
Cristina 跟你直说吧
Cristina,let me be clear.
我不只是想你们增进了解
It's not just that I want the two of you to get to know each other,
我想让Owen觉得跟你在一起非常自在
it's that I want owen to feel comfortable with you.
他跟我在一起的时候可自在了
Oh,he is comfortable with me.
没事的
It's fine.
你和她说 没事的
You can talk to her.It's fine.
好吧 Cristina 他跟你聊天 跟你在一起很自在
okay. Cristina,um,he talks to you,he's comfortable with you.
他跟你聊过心灵创伤不?
Does he talk to you about his trauma?
Owen跟你聊过战争吗?
Does owen talk to you about the war?
跟你聊过那晚...他掐你的事吗?
Does he talk to you about the incident between you two-- the choking?
Owen的创后压力之所以没浮现 是在于他一直逃避谈论战争
Owen's post-traumatic stress is fed... by his avoidance of talking about anything in the war.
如想治愈 他需要和你我谈论
In order to improve,to heal,he's going to have to start talking about it,to you and to me.
我担心的是 如果你们沉迷色欲 他连这头都开不了
And my concern is,if you get lost in the lust of it all,he won't have to make a start.
他没必要那么做
He won't have any reason to.
他可能觉得拥有一切 但最后只会失去
He'll feel that he has everything he needs until he doesn'T.
所以 我想请你等待
So... I'm asking you to wait.
好了
finished.
读给我听
read it back to me.
"嗨 妈妈"
"Hi,mom.
"请先做好心理准备 因为您可能无法接受"
Please prepare yourself,"because this is gonna be difficult to read.
"我出意外了"
I've been in an accident.
跟我说的完全两样
" That's not what I said.
- "我受了极重的伤 动过了17次手术" - 你不能这么发
- "I've suffered terrible injuries and 17 surgeries. - " You can't send that to her.
"我现在腹腔感染"
"Currently,I'm suffering from an abdominal infection,"
"但我拒绝治疗 所以将不久于人世"
which I've refused to treat,so I'm gonna die soon.
"请您尽快赶来 如果您到之前我已离开"
"Please come quickly,mom,"and if I'm gone before you get here,"
- "我想让您知道 我是多么爱您" - 别说了
- I just wanted to tell you how much I love you"...  - stop it.
- "也谢谢您辛苦拉扯了我" - 贱货
-"And to thank you for making me from scratch. - " Bitch.
你真是犯贱
You're a bitch.
我可以按铃叫护士来推你进手术室
I can hit the call button and I can have the nurses in here to take you into surgery,
要不我就发送信息 你自己看着办
or I can hit "send"--that's the deal.
我要告你 还有这间医院
I will sue you.I will sue you and this hospital.
告不了 你马上就没命了
No,you won'T.You'll be dead.
拜托
Please.
你好 护士说你点名要我?
hello.The nurses said you called for me?
这是Andy
This is andy.
Andy Michaelson
Andy michaelson.
不好意思 我之前治疗过你吗?
I'm sorry.Have i treated you before?
Arizona Robbins医生引见的
dr. Arizona robbins referred us.
哦 Andy 你就是那个...
Oh,andy.you're the-- you're the kid with the--
那个不知道得什么病的小孩 没错
with the thing no one can diagnose.Yeah,that's us.
那Robbins医生让你们来西慈医院是想...
okay,so dr. Robbins sent you here to mercy west because...
这是Andy在仁爱医院的病例副本
these are copies of andy's paperwork from seattle grace.
我们无法入睡
we don't sleep anymore.
天天就奔波于医院
We basically just go to the hospital,you know?
我手足无措 觉得自己是不称职的母亲
And I don't know what else to do,'cause I feel like a terrible mother.
- 妈妈 - 我太不称职了 我应该...
- Mom. - I feel like a terrible mother because I'm supposed to...
- 我应该做些事的 但我做不了 - 妈
- I'm supposed to do something,and I can'T. - Mom.
我不是学医的
You know,I didn't go to medical school.
我学的是该死的历史
I majored in freakin' history.
但你们是医生
Y-you're the doctors,you know?
你们可是医生啊
You're the doctors.
基本上来说 我们现在每一个人
And basically,all we've been doing up to this point,any of us,
所有人 就是在让我儿子染上药瘾而已
all we've been doing is getting my kid strung out on these pain meds.
- 妈 别说了 - 不行 Andy
- Mom,stop. - I can't,andy.
我不得不说
I can't stop.
我们无法入睡 我陪他一起失眠 我很害怕
We don't sleep.He can't sleep.We can't sleep.And I'm scared.
Robbins说 她需要你做脊柱三维核磁共振
And dr. Robbins said that what she needs for you to give us is a 3-d M.R.I. Of his spine.
她还说你肯定不肯做 因为没什么迹象之类
And she said you wouldn't want to because there's no indication or whatever,
但她说这有必要 拜托了
but she says that's what he needs.Please.
别让我显得如此无用
I can't be this useless.
还有 你也不能
And you know what?Neither can you.
拜托
Please.
小肠有许多坏疽
that's a lot of necrotic small bowel.
能挽救吗?
can you save any of it?
昨天就可以
Yestery I could have.
昨天只需要一个简单的引流
Yesterday this would've been a simple drainage.
但那是在Yang医生威胁她 做没必要的结肠造口术之前
But that was before dr. Yang threatened my patient with a colostomy that thankfully will not be necessary,
因为这根本和结肠没什么关系
because it did not actually involve the colon.
我能干点什么?
how can I help?
你干得够多的了
Oh,you've done enough.
她提了问题 我如实回答根本没错 这是我的工作
She asked me a question.I was right to answer it.I did my job.
病人要求我说明手术的风险
A patient asked me to disclose the risks of a surgical procedure,
法律及职业道德要求我这么做
and I am required by law and my oath to do so.
你要是有办法粉饰结肠造口术 我洗耳恭听
If you know a way to sugarcoat a colostomy bag,I would like to hear it.
你要是知道该怎么和住院医生说话 我也洗耳恭听
If you know a more respectl way to speak to an attending surgeon,I'd like to hear that.
在你学会之前 别和我说话
Until you do,you don't talk to me.
别跟着我了
You're off my service.
来真的? 你没毛病吧?!
Okay,okay,seriously?What is your problem?!
这么多上层到场? 搞得人心慌慌
more suits?It's freaking people out.
又是减小规模又是企业接管的 有人说Webber要走为上策了
There's talk of downsizing,corporate takeovers,rumors that webber's jumping ship.
你和主任那么熟 他是怎么打算的?
You've got the chief's ear.What's he got planned?
- 这是化验结果 - 谢谢
- here's the test. - thank you.
他要退休了
he's retiring.
他们要选我当主任
They're making me chief.
- 不是吧 - 是的
- No. - Yeah.
- 真的? - 是
- Really? - yeah.
- 真的呀? - 对
- Really?  - Yep.
主任没向我透露过半点风声
I mean,the chief never said anything to me.
要不我肯定要拼命争取
I would've fought you hard for that.
我猜他就是想要你做 祝贺了
Well,I guess if that's what he wants... I guess,uh,congratulations are in order.
等等 你不是... 你逗我玩呢?
wait,that was... you're messing with me?
你太好骗了
It's just too easy.
你可真够卑劣的 知道吗?
You got a meantreak,you know that?
卑劣
Mean.
说真的 到底怎么回事?
seriously,what's going on?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我准备了葡萄酒 白的和红的
oh,I have wine-- white and red.
还有烟 我知道这个不好
And I have cigarettes,which is awful,I know.
但我只在非常非常特殊的情况下才抽 比如现在 我知道自己有麻烦了
But I only smoke 'em very,very,very occasionally,and it's only when I know I'm gonna be in trouble,like now.
太不合适了 愚蠢且操控欲强
It was inappropriate,not to mention manipulative and stupid.
- 你抽烟? - 我知道 听着
- You smoke? - I know.Okay,listen.
我知道你完全有理由生我的气 但我真是没办法了
I know you have every right to be mad at me,but I ran out of options,so--
这个检测非常贵 且没有迹象表明非做不可
it's an expensive test.There was no indication to do it.
Webber不让你做情有可原!
There's a reason webber turned you down!
所以你就没做?
So you didn't do it?
我当然做了 Arizona
Of course I did it,arizona.
- 太谢谢了 - 先别谢我
- Thank you. - No.Don't thank me yet.
没扫描出任何结果
The scan didn't show anything.
啊?! 不会吧 什么都没有?
What?!Come on,nothing?
这看起来不太对劲
No.Okay,now that.That looks a little funny to me.
我也这么觉得 但放射科医生说这很正常
I thought so,too,but the radiologist said it's normal.
好 来吧
oh,okay,all right.Just... here.
他的病史和体检记录有任何异常吗?
Is there anything peculiar about his h&p?
* I'm gonna let you down gonna toss you around *
* I'm gonna let you down   gonna toss you around *
* gonna make you want everything you haven't found *
* I'm gonna hold your hand *
不好意思
sorry!Sorry.
真...抱歉
Just... uh,sorry.
很抱歉
Sorry.We're sorry.
我们会把台子洗干净的
We'll be sure to clean the countertop.
你们以从不这样的 但现在无时不刻 无所不在
Uh,you didn't used to do this before,and now it's kind of all the time,everywhere.
- 我就是有点... - 你知道 我们...
- And--and I didn't--  - yeah,well,you know,it'S...
结婚了 所以...
we're married now and...
就有所改变 抱歉在厨房的台子上做
things have changed a little,but,uh,we're sorry about the countertop.
所以 你们真是那样?
so you guys are-- you're really-- that's it?
那个即时贴 是真的?
The post-it,that's for real?
对 是真的
Yeah,that's for real.
第30天
*****
看什么呢?
what you reading?
一个病例 诊断不出来 快把我逼疯了
Yeah,I got this patient I'm trying to diagnose.It's driving me nuts.
那就休息一下吧 我想你了
So take a break.I miss you.
我就在这啊
Well,I'm right here.
你不在
No,you're not.
你的心不在 我很想你
You're here,but you're not here,and I miss you.
Iz 拜托 我要工作
Iz,come on.I'm trying to work.
我希望长个脑瘤
I'm wishing for a brain tumor.
我一直希望有个大肿瘤能压住大脑
I'm wishing all the time for a giant tumor that would just press down on my brain
让我能臆想出George 和他说说话
and make me hallucinate george... so that I could talk to him again,
和他一起放声大笑
so I could laugh with him again.
我...我真想他啊
I... I miss him... so much.
我一直在想他 我想让自己好一点
I miss him all the time,and I just want to feel better.
一分钟也好 你明白吗?
Even for a minute,younow?
希望自己能有一分钟不想着脑瘤
I just want to be a person who isn't wishing for a brain tumor just for one minute.
因为癌症 我不能喝酒
And I can't drink because of the cancer meds.
我也不吸毒 现在更没法工作
I don't do drugs.I can't even work right now.
没有任何能分散注意力的事
I don't have any distractions.
我好伤心 我真想念George
I'm sad... and I miss george.
拜托 进屋来让我好受一些
So please... please... come inside and help me feel better.
"我想George了" 真有你的
"I miss george." Nice.
真具诱惑性
Real seductive.
第36天
*******
Mark在吗?
Is,uh,mark around?
他在冲澡
He's in the shower.
谢谢
Oh,thanks.
嗨 你知道主任到底怎么回事吗?
Hey,hav have you heard anything about what's happening with the chief?
西慈传得沸沸扬扬的 说他可能到我们那儿工作
There's all these rumors floating around mercy west,like he might be coming to work for us.
这样我的日子可不好过了啊
That would not go well for me.
我什么也没听说 我再去问问Derek
I haven't heard anything.I'll check with derek again.
帮我递一下洗发水
Can you hand me the shampoo?
谢谢
Thank you.
你真的是拉拉吗?
Are you really gay?
到底有多拉拉呢 打几分?
Like,how gay are you,on a scale of--of 1 to gay?
我是说 淋浴的是我男友 赤果果的性感撩人的男友
'Cause that's my boyfriend in--in the shower,my hot,hot,naked boyfriend,
你到底有多拉?
and I... ho-how gay are you?
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我认识Mark很久了 我以后尽量不在他淋浴时这样了
It'S... I've known mark a while,and-- but I'll... I'll try not to do that again-- the naked in the shower thing.
还有你在门厅半裸的事
Or--or the you half-naked in the hallway thing?
即便你是同性恋 但他不是 你又很辣
'Cause--'cause even if you really are gay,he--he's not,and--and you're hot.
他现在看都不看我的胸部
he doesn't look at my boobs anymore.
以前不论我走到哪 他总是第一眼瞟到我的胸部
The first thing he used to look at when I walked in anywhere was my boobs.
自从遇到你 他就不这样了
He doesn't look anymore,not since he met you.
明白了?
Okay?
明白
Okay.
Shepherd
Shepherd.
你真是神龙见首不见尾啊
You're a hard man to track down.
我很忙 你又不是不知道
I'm busy,as you know.
是啊 打着西慈医院的主意呢
Yeah,scoping out mercy west.
要弃我们于不顾了?
You planning on jumping ship?
我觉得 作为朋友
'Cause I assume,as a friend,
你应该透露点信息
you would tell me if there's anything I need to know.
谣言而已 Derek
Those are rumors,derek.
谣言多着呢
There are a lot of rumors.
Jennings不回我电话了
And jennings isn't answering my calls anymore.
你为什么要打给他 Derel?
Why are you calling jennings,derek?
我说过有什么信息 自然会告诉你
I told you I would fill you in when there was something to tell.
要是你想背着我干什么 至少替我...
If you feel the need to go behind my back,at least do me
背着你?
behind your back?
Behind your back?
我可一直全心全意地支持你
I'm the one who's got your back.
别忘了这点
Don't you forget that.
- Shepherd医生 - 嗯
- dr. Shepherd. - Yes.
- 有时间吗? - 什么事?
- Do you have a minute? - For what?
一个有栓系脊髓的患儿
A kid with a tethered spinal cord.
我彻夜难眠 突然灵光一现
I just sat up in the middle of the night,and I thought,
可能是栓系脊髓 但片子看不出来
tethered spinal cord,but you're not gonna see it on there.
还需要相关检查才能确诊
I need to run another test to confirm the diagnosis.
栓系脊髓十分罕见
A tethered cord's pretty rare.
- 他有脊柱裂的病史吗? - 没有
- Does he have a history of spina bifida? - No.
那下背损伤 反射亢进呢?
Lower back lesions,hyperreflexia?
都没有 但当他弯伸脊髓时 疼痛会加重
No and no,but the pain is aggravated when he extends or flexes his spine.
我知道你会说 核磁共振应该能显示出栓系脊髓
I know what you're gonna say-- that the tethered cord should've shown up on the M.R.I.
但要是碰巧不显示呢?
But what if it didn't?
要是他需要的不是再做一次核磁
What if what this kid needs is not another M.R.I.
而是更清楚的CT脊髓成像?
But a much more specific C.T. Myelogram?
也许吧 做个呗
Maybe. Order one.
我不能 要是我做了 很可能会被炒
Well,see,I can't,because if I did,I'd get fired...
我真的好喜欢我的工作
and I really... like my job.
主任不准你做?
Did the chief deny that request?
吃了几次闭门羹了
several times.
你应该一开始就跟我说主任不让的
You shoulda led with the part about the chief.
跟我来
Come on.
- 做得不错 - 又站起来了
- You're doing great. - You're up,girl.
是啊 谁会知道站立都会这么困难呢
I know.Who would've thought standing could be so hard,right?
- 你做得很棒 - 真不错
- You're doing awesome. - Awesome.
- 放我下来 - 再坚持几秒
- Put me down. - Let's go a couple of more seconds.
- 你做得... - 放我下来
- You're doing - put me down.
已经很不错了
that wagreaT.
休息一下 我们再走 怎样?
Take a sec,and then go again for me,okay?
不
No.
我明白 Clara
I know,clara.
但困难才刚刚开始
But this is where the hard part begins.
美梦先生
mcdreamy.
你说什么?
I'm sorry?
我终于知道大家为何叫你美梦先生了
I get it now-- the whole,you know,mcdreamy thing.
以前不太明白
I didn't--I didn't get it before.
但现在懂了
But now I get it.
你知道这个外号 对吧?
You know they call you that,right?
当然
Yes.
我正恋爱 别误会 以为我勾搭你
I'm involved,by the way,in case you thought that I was just coming on to you,
我可没有
because I was not.
而且 我知道你结婚了
Plus,well,I heard that you got married.
恭喜
So congratulations.
谢谢
Yes,thank you.
你们不就在在医生休息室 用即时贴写了些虚情假意的东西吗
you wrote some hokey crap on a post-it note in the resident's lounge.
不过 在你穿着晨礼服大汗淋漓
Sorry,but until you're sweating it out in a morning coat
在新娘穿着礼服向你走来之前
with a ball of white taffeta coming at you,
抱歉 你还不能算已婚
you're not really married.
好吧
oh,okay.
至少我有洞房花烛
Well,I've consummated mine.
而且不止一次呢
I consummate mine all the time.
你呢 Karev?
How's that going for you,karev?
听她们八卦说起的
Girls talk.
等你圆房了 再来评价我的即时贴婚礼吧
You might want to consider that the next time you judge my post-it.
我还没哭过
I haven't cried yet.
我用工作和性爱分心
I'm using work and sex as a distraction,
效果好像还不错
and I think it's working for me.
你有没有看见那个Amanda
Have you seen the girl--amanda
整天坐在医院外的长椅上
sitting outside the hospital on that bench all day long,
- 每个... - 我想做爱
- every - I miss sex.
想死了
Oh,I miss it so muchmuch.
怎么了?
What?
- Mer... - 我很担心Clara
- Mer,wh - I'm worried about clara.
她很消沉
She's depressed.
好像比以前严重得多
But like a whole new level of depressed.
我不知该怎么办
I-I don't know what to do.
你在说那个"酸橘汁腌鱼"?
Are you talking about ceviche?
那个... 天哪
That... oh,my god.
你太恶劣了
That'S... that is so rude.
"酸橘汁腌鱼"?
Ceviche?
太...太...太恶劣了
That is so--that--it-- that's rude.
太恶劣了
That--that-- that is so rude.
还有人愿意让我得罪吗?
Well,anyone else I can offend?
栓系脊髓?
A tethered spinal cord?
一条脊髓线连到了尾骨上
One of the threads in his spinal cord is attached to his tailbone.
一般脊髓下端都是游离的 现在连接尾骨
Normally the spinal cord is free at the end,but with it attached,
你在生长发育时 就会牵拉脊髓
when you grew,it started pulling.
于是产生剧痛
Thus the excruciating pain.
你们能治好吗? 这病能治吗?
So can we fix it?Is it fixable?
微创手术就行了
It's a microsurgery.
我把连上的脊髓剪断 他就不会再痛了
I'll snip the tethered cord,and he'll be free of pain.
她一般不这样
she's not normally like this.
在这之前 她一直是个正常的妈妈
before all this,she was,like,a normal mom.
Andy 现在她就是个正常妈妈
andy,this is a normal mom.
我们在等Swender医生吗?
are we waiting for dr. Swender?
不是
No.
Swender医生把你移交给我
dr. Swender has handed you off to me.
就你 第二年主治医生?
Wh-what are you,like,second year?
第三年
Third.
那也太... 我们是不是要呼下Swender医生?
That's,um... can we page dr. Swender or something?
Stevens 这是好事
Stevens,this is a good thing.
是的
It is.
癌灶依然存在
You still have cancer,
但勾不起Swender医生的兴趣了
but not enough to interest dr. Swender anymore.
这可是件好事
It is a good thing.
你是说我的癌资历太浅?
You're saying I have J.V. Cancer?
我是说你的癌灶大大减小
I'm saying your mets have shrunk way down,
而且没有新发
and there are no new ones.
给你的方案相当有效
Your protocol is working very effectively.
Stevens
Stevens.
这消息好得不能再好了
This is about as good as the news gets.
那...现在该怎么办?
Um... so what-- what now?
目前 我们还是继续在中央静脉管 注射白介素2
We're gonna use the port in your chest to continue with your I.L.-2 regimen for now.
实时关注病情的进展
And we'll continue monitoring the progression of your disease
每隔三或六个月 做一次核素扫描
with pet-scans every three to six months.
这有没有什么时间表 或是...?
Is there,uh,some kind of timeline on this or...
你妻子得了癌症 Karev医生
your wife is living  with cancer,dr. Karev.
而且现在癌灶没有扩大
Right now the cancer has stopped growing.
对于侵袭性如此强的癌症 这可是不小的成就
With a cancer this aggressive,that's pretty stunning success.
不可能有什么时间表
There's no timeline.
我们只能...仔细观察
There's just... we watch it.
耐心等待
We wait.
希望它不会复发
We hope it doesn't start to grow again.
就这样?
That's it?
就这样
that's it.
第37天
DAY 37
我看到胫骨前肌收缩
I see contractions in the anterior tibialus.
好的 那是神经根 不是神经纤维
okay.That's the nerve root,not the filum.
请给我双极管和微创剪刀
Bipolars and the microscissors,please.
你想切吗?
Want to make the cut?
不 没这个必要
No.I-I don't need to.
要不是你
You know,without you,this kid probably would've been
这个病人可能一直会有慢性疼痛 并对止痛药上瘾
a chronic pain patient and possibly addicted to pain meds.
他的未来全靠你
He owes his entire future to you.
应该由你来切
You should make the cut.
好吗?
Okay?
好的
Okay.
置入剪刀
Put the scissor in.
就是这样 做得不错
TherE.Nicely done.
Clara Grey医生说你还是不愿做理疗
clara,dr. Grey says you're still refusing your physical therapy.
我知道这很困难
Now I understand it's hard.
但你必须得锻炼肌肉力量
But you have to rk these muscles now,
要不它们会萎缩 难以恢复正常功能
or they will atrophy and they'll heal incorrectly.
Clara 你必须迈出第一步
Clara,you gotta do the work.
现在就得迈出第一步
You know,you've just got to do the work now.
我知道生不如死的感觉
clara,I know what it is to not want to live,
我也知道失去一切的痛苦
to wish that you'd died,to lose everything...
更知道要告诉母亲 有多么困难
to not want to... call your mother.
相信与否 这一切我都感同深受
Believe it or not,I know exactly what that is.
我曾经也这样消沉
I have been there.
但现在又重振旗鼓
But I am back now.
尽管看似毫无可能 最终...
and as impossible as it felt,eventually...
我重振旗鼓
I came back.
你也可以
And so can you.
但你得迈出第一步
But you have got to do the work.
你得把她送去精神科
you have to get her admitted to psych.
委托给精神科?
Committed?
你希望我委托给精神科?
You want me to have her committed?
我们已无能为力 你得做个决定
There's nothing more we can do.You have to make that call.
人们叫你"酸橘汁腌鱼"
People are calling you "ceviche.
- Grey医生 你得... - 我的意思是...
- dr. Grey,you - I mean,that's,you know...
你不能出院后还让人叫你"酸橘汁腌鱼"
you can't go out like that,clara,with people calling you ceviche.
"酸橘汁腌鱼"?
Ceviche?
是道菜
Yeah,it--it's a meal.
可能是秘鲁菜吧
It'S... peruvian,I think.
就是剁碎的鱼肉
I... it's chopped up fish.
真糟糕 对吧?
that is really horrible,isn't it?
是啊 太糟糕了
it is. It'S... it's--it's horrible.
第39天
DAY 39
我没料到会这样
I didn't expect this.
当人们说"晚期癌症"时 意味着你命不久矣
They say "cancer," they say "stage iv," you expect to die.
接着你开始想 没准我能战胜它
And then you start thinking,well,maybe I can kick it.
也许在我身上会发生奇迹
Maybe I'll be the miracle.
是啊 你就是奇迹
Well,you are the miracle.
癌症依然伴随着我
I'm still living with cancer.
我只是...
You know,I just...
没料到会这样
you don't expect that.
那不是George救的那女孩吗?
Isn't that the girl that george saved?
Amanda
Amanda.
是的
Yeah.
她在这儿干吗?
What is she doing here?
她整天都坐在那
Oh,she sits there,every day,all day.
上帝啊
Oh,for god sakes.
你要...
Where--where what
起来
get up.
我说真的 起来
I mean it,get up.
起 来
Get up.
去好好生活
now go get a life.
我做不到
I can'T.
George生前是个外科医生
George was a surgeon.
他的梦想就是能救死扶伤
He had a purpose.He wanted to save lives.
但现在他没机会了
And now he doesn't get the chance.
他再也没机会做什么了 但你可以
Now he doesn't get the chance to do anything anymore,but you do.
你可以去医学院
You could go to medical school,you know?
你可以和朋友一起消磨时光
You uld hang out with your freakin' friends.
我不管你做什么
I don't care what you do.
但去做点什么 因为你有生命!
Just go do something with your life,because you have one.
你还活着
You lived.
你还活着 但George不在了
You lived and george didn'T.
我知道
And I know.
我...知道这种恐惧无助的感觉
I... I know... that that feels horrible and shocking... and terrifying.
但起码你活着
But you lived.
所以放手去生活吧
So go live your freakin' life.
我不知道该怎么做
I... I don't know how.
没人知道
Nobody does.
没人知道要怎么做
Nobody knows how.
但就算是为了George 你得去摸索
But god,have enough respect for george to figure it out.
如果我再看见你坐在这里无所事事
'Cause if I see you sitting on this bench ever again,
我会狠狠地收拾你
I will kick your ass from here to sunday.
我不能再跟Bailey的病例了
I can't get back on bailey's service.
她看都不看我一眼
I mean,she's still not even looking at me.
给她点时间
You just gotta give it time.
她和O'malley很亲 而且工作...
You know,she was close with o'malley,and she's working--
但问题是 这根本与O'malley无关
yeah,but the thing is,it's not even about o'malley.
她是因为酸橘汁腌鱼而生我的气
I mean,she's mad at me about ceviche.
别再这么说了
you gotta stop that.
酸橘汁腌鱼?
Ceviche?
呃...是个病人
Oh,it's a--it's a patient.
船难的受害人
A boating accident victim.
她想给她起个海鲜菜肴的名字
She thinks that it's okay to call her a seafood dish.
- 这是道美味的秘鲁菜 - 我是说 这没问题吧?
- It's a delicious peruvian dish. - I mean,is that is that okay?
有点阴暗
Well,it's pretty dark.
不是吧 我阴暗?
Oh,come on.I'm dark?
我可没在别人睡觉时试图掐死她
I'm not the one gog around choking people in their sleep.
什么?
What?
太快了?
too soon?
我不想在别人睡觉时掐死她
I'm not the guy going around choking people in their sleep.
- 我知道 - 我当时做了噩梦
- I know. - It was a dream.
我想不起来是什么梦了
I... I can't remember what I was dreaming about,
但我当时是为了救自己一命
but... I was trying to save my own life.
我不想伤害你
I wasn't trying to hurt you.
我只是...
I was...
我是在争取自己的生命
I was fighting for my life.
好的
Okay.
你开了个好头
you made a start.
终于敞开心扉了
You made a start.
你可以的 Clara 你可以的
you have it,clara. You have it.
你能做到
You've got this.
好样的
yeah,girl.
- 我做到了 - 你做到了
- I did it. - You did it.
我做到了
I did it.
Lexie
Lexie.
能给我妈妈打个电话吗?
Will you call my mum?
当然
Yeah. Yeah.
好 再来
okay,come on. come on.
做得好
Good. yeah.
就这样
You got it.
悲伤人皆有之
grief may be a thing  we all have in common...
于每人却各不相同
but it looks different  on everyone.
嗨
Hey
并非只有死亡才让人悲伤
it isn't just death  we have to grieve.
还有生活 痛失 改变
It's life...  it's loss...  it's change.
当我们想不通为何不如意接踵而至
and when we wonder  why it has to suck  so much sometimes,
为何人生如此痛彻心扉
has to hurt so bad...
我们应记住 乌云会随时消散
the thing  we gotta try to remember is that it can turn on a dime...
这是做什么?
what is this?
把裤子脱掉
Take off your pants.
Iz 这...
Iz,it's,uh...
像个丈夫的样子
be my husband.
把衣服脱了 上床 抱着我
Get undressed,get into bed and hold me.
我不知道你在生什么气
I don't know what you're so mad about a
也不知道你在害怕什么 因为你根本不愿和我说话
nd I don't know what you're scared of because you won't talk to me.
我也很害怕 Alex 你这样我没办法...
But I'm scared,too,alex,and I-I can't--if you won't--
如果我们想生活在一起
if we're gonna have any chance at a life together,
我需要你... 求你了
then I need you to... please.
你曾死在我的怀里
You died in my arms.
你突然就死了 又明确指示我不能救你
You freakin' died and then you left instructions that I wasn't allowed to save your life.
你想知道我在怕什么?
You want to know what I'm scared of?
我什么都害怕!
I'm scared of everything!
我不敢动 不敢呼吸 不敢碰你!
I'm scared to move! I'm scared to breathe! I'm scared to touch you!
没了你 我活不下去
I can't lose you. I won't survive.
这都是你的错!
And that's your fault.
你让我爱上你 你走进我的生活
You made me love you,you made me let you in,
然后你就死在我的怀里!
and then you freakin' die in my arms!
这样你才能活下去
that's how you stay alive.
当疼痛让你无法呼吸
When it hurts so much  you can't breathe,
这就是你活下去的方式
that's how you survive...
Miranda
miranda.
我们要牢记 总有一天
by remembering  that one day,
无论以何种方式 无论多么不可能
somehow...  impossibly...
这种感觉会不再继续
it won't feel this way.
生活不再这般痛苦
It won't hurt this much.
听着 我是一个主治医生
look,I... I am an attending,
一个单身母亲
and I am a single mother,
我没能救活O'malley
and I lost o'malley... and,um...
我...不能再这么在乎了
I just can't-- I-I can't care anymore.
Stevens不是我的孩子
Stevens is not my child.
O'malley也不是
O'malley was not my child.
我不能再把他们...
I have to stop treating... I...
我不能再这样念念不忘
I just have to stop caring so much.
我不能在工作时有这样的感觉
'cause I can't keep fe-- feeling like this,n-not at work.
我要把感情留给我的儿子 他需要
I have to save the feeling for my son,who needs it.
我不能再到处浪费感情了
So I just can't keep giving it away he.
我不会了
I c--I won'T.
悲伤不请自至 无人幸免
grief comes  in its own time for everyone...
各不相同
in its own way.
我们最好的选择
so the best we can do...
所有人最好的选择
the best anyone can do...
就是坦诚面对
is try for honesty.
我不想再伤害你
I don't want to hurt you again.
我的问题真实存在
my problems,they're real.
这也让我们变得真实
And this,this makes us real.
我的问题你也需要面对
It makes my problems your problems.
我很担心
I'afraid.
我不想再伤害你
I don't want to hurt you again.
你可以在浴缸里睡觉
you can sleep in the bathtub.
什么?
what?
最让人不舒服的...
the really crappy thing,
关于悲伤最让人讨厌的 就是我们无法控制它
the very worst part of grief,is that you can't control it.
你在干什么?
what are you doing?
我们需要腾出地方
We need the space.
我们能做的就是 当它来时切身感受
the best we can do  is try to let ourselves feel it  when it comes...
嗨
hey.
谢谢
Thank you.
我今天被实习生缠住了
I was stuck with this intern today.
他试了4次才插入中心静脉导管
It took him four tries to throw in a central line.
让我想起了当初的George
Reminded me a little bit of george,actually,
在他做实习生的时候
when he was an intern.
如果可以 适时放手
and let it go  when we can.
Meredith
meredith.
更糟糕的是 当你以为它已经远去了
the very worst part  is that the minute you think you're past it,
它却卷土重来
it starts all over again
每次想起
and always,every time... george o'malley died.
George O'malley死了
你都无法呼吸
it takes your breath away.
第40天
DAY 40
悲伤有五个阶段
there are  five stages of grief.
虽然每人情况各不相同 但都可以分为五个阶段
They look different  on all of us,but there are always five...
我知道你们听到不少传言
I know you all have heard a lot of rumors.
我感到十分抱歉
And I'm sorry for that.
否认
- denial... - and what I'm about to say will be hard to hear,
接下来要说的你们可能很难接受
对此我也很抱歉
and I'm sorry for that as well.
愤怒
anger... the economic climate is...
经济形势非常...
你们都知道情况怎样
well,you all know what it is.
接下来几周 仁爱医院将和西慈医院合并
In the coming weeks,seattle grace hospital will be merging with mercy west.
交涉
bargaining...
真希望我能告诉大家你们都会留下来
I wish I could tell you you will all survive the merger,
但是职位有限
but there are only so manyobs,
董事会和我将进行艰难抉择
and the board and I have some tough choices to make.
消沉
depression...
我站在你们这边
I'm on your side,people.
我支持你们每个人
I'm rooting for every onof you.
我只能说
All I can say is,
希望你们拿出最好的状态
please... be at your very best.
接受
acceptance.
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=- 翻译: mmowen 小跑步的熊 蓉蓉 cctv will uu里 马蚤 校对: 蓉蓉 uu里 时间轴: 消 猪 泡 猪二
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-Sync:YTET-消 猪 泡 猪二
-=医人当自强 第六季 第1&2集完=-
Greys.anatomy Season6 Episode1 2